All the adventure your imagination can hold.
The Pagemaster is a family, fantasy, animation film directed by Pixote Hunt.
Rich knows a lot about accidents.
So much so, he is scared to do anything that might endanger him,
like riding his bike, or climbing into his treehouse.
While in an old library, he is mystically transported into the unknown
world of books, and he has to try and get home again.
Richard Tyler, played by Macaulay Culkin.
Mr. Dewey, played by Christopher Lloyd.
Fantasy (voice), played by Whoopi Goldberg.
Adventure (voice), played by Patrick Stewart.
Horror (voice), played by Frank Welker.
Dr. Jekyll / Mr. Hyde (voice), played by Leonard Nimoy.
The Pagemaster is a 1994 American live-action animated fantasy adventure film starring Macaulay Culkin, Christopher
Lloyd, Whoopi Goldberg, Patrick Stewart, Leonard Nimoy, Frank Welker, Ed Begley Jr., and Mel Harris.
The film was produced by Colbath and Hanna-Barbera and released by 20th
Century Fox and Turner Pictures on November 23, 1994.
Culkin stars as a timid boy who uses statistics as an excuse to
avoid anything he finds uncomfortable in life.
But after reluctantly undertaking an errand for his father, he gets caught
in a storm, which forces him to seek refuge in a library.
He then finds himself trapped inside the library, where he must battle his way
through literary classics come to life if he is to find his way home.
The film was written for the screen by David Casci, based on a six-page pitch by writer Charles
Pogue entitled "Library Days", presented to Casci by producer David Kirschner.
The film was directed by Joe Johnston (live-action) and Pixote Hunt and Glenn
Chaika (animation), and produced by David Kirschner and Paul Gertz.
The film received generally negative reviews from critics and
grossed $13.7 million from a budget of $34 million.
The film's poor box office performance, along with the 1997 film Cats Don't Dance (which was in production at the time The
Pagemaster was released), set back other animated films for the animation studio, Turner Feature Animation.
The film explores themes of rain, animated scene,
bike, live action and animation.